Rush family papers LCP.Rush
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series I. Benjamin Rush papers
  - Subseries VII. Professorship at University of Pennsylvania
    - B. Lectures, Yi2 7394; Yi2 7395; Yi2 7396; Yi2 7397; Yi2 7398; Yi2 7399; Yi2 7400]
      - On fevers: On drunkenness and its cures, undated; [7399 F 38] (Volume 267)
      - On fevers: Diseases and disorders of the liver, undated; [7399 F 39, 7399 F 40] (Volume 268-269)
      - On fevers: Of the colic, undated; [7399 F 41, 7399 F 42] (Volume 270-271)
      - On fevers: Choria, hiccup, and cramp, undated; [7399 F 43] (Volume 272)
      - On fevers: Ricketts, ringworm, etc., undated; [7399 F 44, 7399 F 45] (Volume 273-274)
      - On fevers: On the diseases and disorders of children, undated; [7399 F 46] (Volume 275)
      - On fevers: Of diarrhea, undated; [7399 F 47] (Volume 276)
      - On fevers: On parturition, undated; [7399 F 48] (Volume 277)
      - On fevers: Observations on the diseases of pregnancy and parturition and the means of curing them, undated; [7399 F 49] (Volume 278)
      - On fevers: On the diseases of women, undated; [7399 F 50] (Volume 279)
      - On fevers, undated; [7401 F 4] (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Cases of chronic diseases [notes possibly used for lectures], 1770; [7400 F 30] (Volume 280)
      - Introductory lecture to a course on the theory and practice of Physic, 1789 November 2; [7400 F 1] (Volume 281)
      - Introductory lecture to a course on the institutes of medical and clinical practice, delivered in the University of Pennsylvania, 1794 November 3; [7400 F 2] (Volume 282)
      - Introductory lecture on the certainty of medicine, 1795 December 2, 1797 December 28; [7400 F 3] (Volume 283)
      - Introductory lecture on imposture in medicine, 1796 November 17; [7400 F 5] (Volume 284)
      - Introductory lecture to the vexations and distresses of medical life, 1797 November 17; [7400 F 6] (Volume 285)
      - Address [Valedictory address for Philadelphia College], 1800 May 31, 1810 April 18; [7400 F 31] (Volume 286)
      - Valedictory lecture on the Institutes of Medicine, 1796 February 19, 1800 March 18; [7400 F 4] (Volume 287)
      - Valedictory lecture, Introductory lecture, 1801, 1804; [7400 F 7] (Volume 288)
      - Introductory lecture on the connection of theory with practice, 1803, 1806; [7400 F 12] (Volume 289)
      - Lecture on the means of preventing summer and autumnal diseases, 1804 January 17; [7400 F 8] (Volume 290)
      - "Facts and Comments on Moral Derangement" as exemplified chiefly in murder (includes newspaper clippings, but does not contain judges' opinions), circa 1804; [7400 F 20] (Volume 301)
      - A valedictory lecture, 1806, 1808, 1810; [7400 F 9] (Volume 291)
      - Lecture on therapeutics, 1807 January 3; [7400 F 11] (Volume 292)
      - [Lecture and outline for course, 1807; [7400 F 10] (Volume 293)
      - Introductory lecture upon the method of studying medicine, 1811 November 4; [7400 F 13] (Volume 294)
      - Valedictory address, 1811; [7400 F 14] (Volume 295)
      - Valedictory address, 1812 February 29; [7400 F 15] (Volume 296)
      - Introductory lecture upon the duties of physicians to each other, 1812 November 1, 1812; [7400 F 16] (Volume 297)
      - First effort in physic, the historia morbi, and diagnosis, causes, prognosis, and methods of the putrid bilious fever, dedicated to William Cullen, undated; [7400 F 17] (Volume 298)
      - Introduction to lectures on the practice of medicine, nosology, undated; [7400 F 18, 7400 F 19] (Volume 299-300)
      - Of Diseases and disorders of the organs of voice and speech, undated; [7400 F 21] (Volume 302)
      - Diseases of the sense of smelling, taste and touch and on the diseases from cold, heat and famine, undated; [7400 F 22] (Volume 303)
      - Deafness, undated; [7400 F 23] (Volume 304)
      - Demance, undated; [7400 F 24] (Volume 305)
      - On the diseases of the passions and the moral faculty, undated; [7400 F 25] (Volume 306)
      - Weakness as the absence of passions, undated; [7400 F 26] (Volume 307)
      - On the venereal diseases, undated; [7400 F 27] (Volume 308)
      - Diseases of the male and female organs of generation, undated; [7400 F 28] (Volume 309)
      - On the bilious of the yellow fever, undated; [7400 F 29] (Volume 310)
      - On Miracles, undated; [7401 F 2] (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - C. Student Work and Review of Student Work, [Yi2 7401, 7402, 7404 and 7406]
      - Notes for students, undated; [7400 F 32] (Volume 311)
      - Manuscript commentary on students' theses, 1809 April; [7404 F 12] (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Student thesis: On Tetanus, by John Briscoe, 1811 April; [7401 F 10] (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Student thesis: Dysentery, by William Buchanan, 1811 April; [7401 F 11] (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Student thesis: On Tetanus, by Henry Charles Glover, 1811; [7401 F 13] (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Student thesis: Pneumonia Biliosa, by James Mayrl, undated; [7401 F 15] (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Student thesis: Modus Operando of Cold, by Samuel Merry, undated; [7401 F 16] (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Student thesis: On respiration, by John D. Perkins, 1811; [7401 F 19] (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Student thesis: On Mania, by Joseph F. See, 1811; [7401 F 14] (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Student thesis: On Conception, by James Stewart, 1811 April; [7401 F 20] (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Remarks and Observations, by Pupils of the Veterinary Institution of the College of London for Dissemination in America, 1812 October; [7401 F 5] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Subseries VIII. Collected writings and notes by others
    - Sermons by Charles Nesbit, 1781-1782; [7402 F 8] (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - An Account of 3 Aged People, by Dr. Sayre, 1789 July 16; [7402 F 37] (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Treatise on Medical Electricity, by Moses Willard, 1789 September; [7401 F 22] (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Medical case of James Woodhouse (former student of Rush), 1792; [7402 F 48] (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Medical case of Simon Williams, 1793 May 29; [7402 F 54] (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Letter from Charles Brockden Brown to James Brown (brother) regarding yellow fever in Philadelphia in 1793, 1796 October 25; [7402 F 17] (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - "Medical Prejudice," by S. Mitchell, 1801 June 11; [7401 F 17] (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Essay on the Utility of Clinical Lectures for Doctor Rush," by Dr. Thomas Bond, 1806 January 6; [7401 F 9] (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "Inquiry Concerning the Uses of the Ventricles of the Brain," by David Watson, 1813 January 1; [7401 F 21] (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - "A Synoptical View of the Human Passions," by Reverend Samuel Davies, undated; [7401 F 12] (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Autobiography of General Stevens, undated; [7406 F 36] (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "On Teaching," by Thomas Hall, undated; [7401 F 8] (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Poem and painting by Richard Nisbett, undated; [7401 F 7] (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "Tranquility--An Ode," by Richard Nisbett, an insane man in the Pennsylvania Hospital, undated; [7401 F 18] (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - On the Improvement and Settlement of Western Lands, by James Wilson, undated; [7401 F 18] (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Series II. James Rush papers
  - Subseries I. Diaries
    - Journal of a Voyage across the Atlantic in the Year 1809, 1809 July-August (Volume 314)
    - During part of a stay in Scotland (16 parts), 1809-1810 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - An Occasional Record of Events and Observations beginning in the Year 1830 (includes entries on his dismissal from the United States Mint by Jackson and the character of his replacement, William Findlay; the death of Stephen Girard; and a biography of his dog, Sid, 1830-1842 (Volume 315)
    - Small Memoranda (includes short entries of a daily journal including notes on the Abolition Hall riot of 1838, introduction of macadamized roads to Philadelphia, suspension of specie payments in 1839, a brutal murder, and his horse Ben and his dog Sid., 1838-1844 (Volume 316)
    - Journal of European travels, 1845-1847 (Volume 317)
    - Journal of European travels, 1846 (Volume 318)
  - Subseries II. Commonplace books
    - Regarding medicine, 1812 (Volume 319)
    - Notes from Readings and Observations upon Characters in the World (includes quotes and paraphrases by famous men on the professions, on moods, on attitudes, etc.), 1813-1838 (Volume 320)
    - Maxims and Quotes, 1824 (Volume 321)
    - Principally extracts from readings, 1827-1832 (Volume 322)
    - Physicians Tricks, Sentences, Essay Topics, 1832 (Volume 323)
    - Notebook with synopses of books on music, the stage, rhetoric and literature, 1832-1838 (Volume 324)
    - On the Mint, Voice, Actors, Inconsistencies (includes notes on the wastage of bullion in the striking of coins, and thoughts on James Rush's Philosophy of the Human Voice), 1832-1838 (Volume 325)
    - Detached thought and extracts from various readings on the practice of medicine by the ancients, 1835 (Volume 326)
    - Regarding fine arts (on Rome, the Parthenon, etc. and including extensive quotes), 1840 (Volume 327)
    - Regarding ideas for 14th Street House, 1849-1850 (Volume 328)
  - Subseries III. Writings by Dr. James Rush
    - Valedictory address to the senior class at Princeton (unpublished), 1804 September 26 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Oration at Nassau Hall (unpublished), 1804 December (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Composition (unpublished), 1804 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - College Tune (unpublished), 1805; [Yi2 70370D] (Volume 329)
    - A Short Account of Gothic Architecture (unpublished), 1811 (Volume 330)
    - Philosophy of the Human Voice: 1st outline, 1823 (Volume 331)
    - Philosophy of the Human Voice: 1st notes and writings, book first, 1823-1824 (Volume 332)
    - Philosophy of the Human Voice: 1st notes and writings, book second, 1824-1825 (Volume 333)
    - Philosophy of the Human Voice: 1st notes and writings, book third, 1824-1826 (Volume 334)
    - Philosophy of the Human Voice: 1st notes and writings, book fourth, 1823-1825 (Volume 335)
    - Philosophy of the Human Voice: 1st notes and writings, book fifth, 1825-1826 (Volume 336)
    - Philosophy of the Human Voice: 1st notes and writings, book sixth, 1825-1826, 1833 (Volume 337)
    - Philosophy of the Human Voice: Printer's copy, 1827 January (Volume 338)
    - Hamlet: A Dramatic Prelude in Five Acts: Second draft, circa 1834 (Volume 339)
    - Hamlet: A Dramatic Prelude in Five Acts: Second writing, circa 1834 (Volume 340)
    - Hamlet: A Dramatic Prelude in Five Acts: Printer's copy, circa 1834 (Volume 341)
    - Hints for a New System of Medicine: Volume 1, Table of Contents and A History of Medicine (unpublished), 1835 December (Volume 342)
    - Hints for a New System of Medicine: Volume 2, First Drafts of Certain Projected Chapters (unpublished), 1835 November 14-1839 August 18 (Volume 343)
    - Hints for a New System of Medicine: Volume 3, History of Medicine after Galen (continued from page 135 of Volume 1) (unpublished), undated (Volume 344)
    - Hints for a New System of Medicine: Volume 5, Occasional Thoughts on Medicine (unpublished), 1836 January 1-1843 February 1 (Volume 345)
    - Abstract of Authors on the Human Voice (unpublished), 1837-1838 (Volume 346)
    - Physical History of the Intellect: Minute Book, circa 1865 (Volume 347-348)
    - Physical History of the Intellect: Printer's copy, volumes 1 and 2, 1865 (Volume 349-350)
    - Natural History of the Intellect: Printer's copy (2nd edition, volumes 1 and 2), 1865 (Volume 351-352)
    - Rhyme and Contrast on Wisdom and Folly: Printer's copy (2nd edition), 1869 (Volume 353)
    - "Notes on the Nature of English Versification, 7 Extracts from Sheridan's Art of Reading" (unpublished), undated (Volume 354)
    - Anecdotes (unpublished), undated; [Yi2 7406 F44] (Volume 355-356)
    - Facts, Thoughts, Etc. regarding medicine (unpublished), undated; [Yi2 7406 F45] (Volume 357)
    - Verses (unpublished), undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Manuscripts (including one biographical sketch of Dr. Benjamin Rush) (unpublished), undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - From a drawing by James Rush (probably relating to Hamlet), undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Copyright certificates for the Philosophy of the Human Voice and Hamlet, 1827-1845 (Box 5, Folder 9-12)
  - Subseries IV. Correspondence, circa 1813-1869
    - A. General Correspondence, bound volumes
      - A-C, Volume 1, circa 1813-1869; [Yi2 7275] (Volume 358)
      - D-G, Volume 2, circa 1813-1869; [Yi2 7276] (Volume 359)
      - H-L, Volume 3, circa 1813-1869; [Yi2 7277] (Volume 360)
      - M-Q, Volume 4, circa 1813-1869; [Yi2 7278] (Volume 361)
      - R-S, Volume 5, circa 1813-1869; [Yi2 7279] (Volume 362)
      - T-Z, Volume 6, circa 1813-1869; [Yi2 7280] (Volume 363)
      - First copies of letters written by James Rush, 1835-1843 (Volume 364)
    - B. General Correspondence, unbound letters, [Yi2 7403-Yi2 7406]
      - Academie Royale des Sciences, 1830 June 7 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - A Friend to the Poor, 1860 February 13 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Anslee, [P.J.], 1814 December 27 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - American Philosophical Society, 1827 July-August (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Ashmead, E., 1860 January 24 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Barber, Sarah, 1867 November 24 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Barton, William, 1811, 1830, 1840 (Box 5, Folder 19-21)
      - Blake, Mr., 1828 December (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Briggs, John H. of the Philoclean Society of Rutgers College, 1833 November 3 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Bryant, William, 1834 August 1 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Butler, P., 1813 April (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Carey and See, 1826-1827 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Coxe, John Redman, 1834-1835 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Craven, [Thomas], 1867 October 3 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Cullen, Charles Sinclair, 1811 August 3 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Cuthbert, Emily, 1820 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Cuthbert, E., 1804, 1834 (Box 5, Folder 31-32)
      - Cuthbert, James, 1836, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 33-34)
      - Cuthbert, Ross, 1815 November 18 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Eberle, James, 1827 May 16 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Emerton, George B., 1835 July 11 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Fisher, Joshua Francis (includes Assemblies ticket), 1831 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Fry, William, 1833, September 3 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Gibson, John, 1845 July 2 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Hale, S.J., 1859 June 25 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Hall, Thomas, 1816 April 16 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Harrison, R., 1831 January 12 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Hewson, Thomas J., 1840 October 28 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Jones, Mrs. A.M., 1862 January 13 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Jones, M.H., 1833 May 1 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Littell, E., 1830 October 5 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Manners, John, 1814 March 8 (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Manners, Mary, 1810-1811, 1835 (Box 5, Folder 49-51)
      - Manners, Robert, 1834 January 9 (Box 5, Folder 52)
      - McIlvaine, Ellen, 1857 February 6 (Box 5, Folder 53)
      - Mercantile Library Company, 1841 May (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Miller, J., 1840 June 26 (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - Moore, Samuel, 1831 (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - Morellis, Cav. D., 1838-1839 (Box 5, Folder 57)
      - Morpeth, 1845 June 23 (Box 5, Folder 58)
      - Murray, undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
      - Neill, Henry, 1840, undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
      - Old Times, 1848 January 12 (Box 5, Folder 61)
      - Peale, J., undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
      - Pennsylvania Hospital, 1813 May 5 (Box 5, Folder 63)
      - Phillips, Henry M., 1840 October 23 (Box 5, Folder 64)
      - Philosophical Society of Rutgers College, 1834 January 10 (Box 5, Folder 65)
      - Phoenix Hose Company, 1841 June 28 (Box 5, Folder 66)
      - Priestly, Joseph and Elizabeth regarding and including deeds, 1814 May (Box 5, Folder 67)
      - Ray, Alex, 1852 June 8 (Box 5, Folder 68)
      - Ridgeway, Edith G., 1858 February 17 (Box 5, Folder 69)
      - Ridgeway, J., 1837 October 2 (Box 5, Folder 70)
      - Ridgeway, Jacob, 1840, 1841 (Box 5, Folder 71-72)
      - Ridgeway, J.J., 1858 November 30 (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - Rotch Elisa, 1824 March 29 (Box 5, Folder 74)
      - Rouse, J.S., 1838 May 16 (Box 5, Folder 75)
      - Royal Infirmary, Edinburgh, 1809 May 1 (Box 5, Folder 76)
      - Royal Society, 1827 June 27 (Box 5, Folder 77)
      - Rush, Anna Maria, letter regarding sale of Sydenham, 1862 January 31 (Box 5, Folder 78)
      - Rush, Arabella, 1862 March 1 (Box 5, Folder 79)
      - Rush, Mrs. A.R., 1841, 1844-1845 (Box 5, Folder 80)
      - Rush, Dr. Benjamin, 1801-1811 (Box 5, Folder 81-86)
      - Rush, Dr. Benjamin and Julia, 1803-1804, 1809-1819 (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
      - Rush, Benjamin (brother of James Rush), 1803-1804 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
      - Rush, Benjamin (nephew of James Rush), 1838-1839, 1864-1868 (Box 6, Folder 9-12)
      - Rush, Catherine E., 1810, 1813, 1828 (Box 6, Folder 13-15)
      - Rush, Jacob, 1815 March 1 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Rush, James to Mrs. Louisa Livingston, 1895 December (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Rush, James to family, 1809 October-December (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Rush, James to unknown recipients, 1813-1819 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Rush, James to his wife, Anna, 1820, 1824, 1825 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Rush, James, 1822-1830 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Rush, James, 1833-1835 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Rush, James, 1840 November (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Rush, James [regarding Library Company of Philadelphia], 1840-1841 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Rush, James, 1852-1868 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Rush, James, 1853 August (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Rush, James Murray, 1843 May 3 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Rush, Julia (mother of James Rush), 1801-1822, undated (Box 6, Folder 28-36)
      - Rush, Julia (sister of James Rush), 1802-1810 (Box 6, Folder 37-39)
      - Lincoln, J. Rush, 1865 October 18 (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - Rush, Mary (sister of James Rush), 1801-1802 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - Rush Mary (cousin of James Rush), 1834 August 10 (Box 6, Folder 42)
      - Rush, Richard H. (nephew of James Rush), 1867 (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - Rush R., James Rush, and James Monroe regarding appointment as Treasurer of the Mint of the United States, 1813 (Box 6, Folder 44)
      - Rush, Samuel, 1822 February 12 (Box 6, Folder 45)
      - Rush, Sarah Catharine, 1862 March 31 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - Rush, William (includes correspondence to other family, in addition to James Rush), 1848-1861 (Box 6, Folder 47-48)
      - Salazar, Joe, 1829 July 27 (Box 6, Folder 49)
      - Sanderson, J.M., 1844 June 7 (Box 6, Folder 50)
      - Scull, Hannah, 1866 December 5 (Box 6, Folder 51)
      - Small, R.A., 1829 October (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - Stockton, E. Boudinot, 1815 April 13 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - Stockton, Julia T., 1857 June 20 (Box 6, Folder 54)
      - Stockton, L.H., 1847 January 2 (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - Stockton, Mary F., 1810 January 10 (Box 6, Folder 56)
      - Stockton, R. [L.], 1830 May 8 (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - Stockton, Richard, 1832, undated (Box 6, Folder 58-59)
      - Stockton, R.F., 1816 January 30 (Box 6, Folder 60)
      - Tawse, John, 1811 April 8 (Box 6, Folder 61)
      - Taylor, W., 1811 February 25 (Box 6, Folder 62)
      - Thomas, James W., 1850 July 20 (Box 6, Folder 63)
      - Tilghman, Augusta, 1860 June 29 (Box 6, Folder 64)
      - Tyson, J.R., 1837 (Box 6, Folder 65)
      - Unknown author, 1846 June 13 (Box 6, Folder 66)
      - Van Buren, Martin regarding position as Treasurer of the United States, 1830 October 4 (Box 6, Folder 67)
      - Van Dyke, J.C. regarding the Philoclean Society, 1839, undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
      - Van Dyke, Rush, 1835 March 14 (Box 6, Folder 69)
      - Vaughan, P., 1845 June 27 (Box 6, Folder 70)
      - Welsh, Mary, 1857 November (Box 6, Folder 71)
      - William, H.J., 1847, undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
      - Woodhouse, James, 1806 November (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - C. Dr. James and Mrs. Phoebe Rush's invitations, acceptances and rejections of social events, [Yi2 7407 -Yi2 7413]
      - Mrs. Rush's invitation list, 1830-1840 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Allen, E., undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Alsop, Mr. Richard and Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Amory, Mrs. And Miss, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Artot, Madame, 1843 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Ashburton, [Alex Baring, first baron], undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Ashhurst, W.H, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Ashhurst, Miss, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Ashmead, Miss, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Aspinwall, Mr. and Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Atherton, Mr., Mrs. and Miss, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Auckland, George Eden, 1st Earl, 1845 June 19-20 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Bache, Major and Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Baker, Mr., undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Bancker, Mrs. and Miss, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Barclay, W.W.W., undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Barclay, Mr. and Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Barker, Mrs. Mary [invitation to funeral of], undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Barry, Mrs. and Miss, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Bartlett, Mr. and Mrs. [cards and invitations], undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Barton, Mr. and Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Bathurst, J.S., undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Bayard, James A., Jr., 1843 January 17 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Baynard, Dr., undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Baynton, Eliza [invitation to funeral of], 1843 December 14 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Beale, John B. [invitation to funeral of], undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Beasley, Dr. and Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Beck, Dr. and Mr. H.P., undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Beckett, Henry, 1834, 1841, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Bell, J. and F, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Betson, Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Beylard, Mr. and Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Bicknell, Mr. and Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Biddle, Mr., Mrs. and Miss, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - Biddle, C., undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - Biddle, C. and J.A., undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - Biddle, C.C. and Mrs., 1840-1850, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Biddle, E.C. and Charles J., undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Biddle, Charles J., undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Biddle, Mrs. G.W., undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
      - Biddle, Mrs. J., undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
      - Biddle, Mr. and Mrs. James C., undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
      - Biddle, J.J., undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
      - Biddle, [Commander] James, undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
      - Biddle, James N., undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
      - Biddle, Mrs. John, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
      - Biddle, Julia W. [to uncle], undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
      - Biddle, Dr. J.B. and Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
      - Biddle, N., 1832-1840, undated (Box 7, Folder 49)
      - Biddle, Mr. and Mrs. Thomas, undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
      - Biddle, Mrs. William, undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
      - Biddle, William S., 1835 June 1 (Box 7, Folder 52)
      - Bille, Mr. and Mrs. De, 1834, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Binney, Mr., Mrs. and Miss, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - Black, J.R., undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
      - Blake, Mrs., undated (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - Blight, Mr. and Mrs. Charles, 1834, undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
      - Blysan, Monsieur, undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - Bohlen, John, undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Bollmann, Miss, undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
      - Bradbury, Mr., 1844 October 9 (Box 7, Folder 61)
      - Bradford, Thomas, 1838 May 8 (Box 7, Folder 62)
      - Brashears, Mr., undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
      - Bray, Mrs. W.K., undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
      - Breck, Mr., undated (Box 7, Folder 65)